GABRIEL CHEN

569 Colusa Ave, El Cerrito, CA 94530 | (510) - 520 - 6239 | gabrielchen@berkeley.edu | gabriel-chen.github.io

PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Python, C/C++, Java, SQL, Git, and Linux/Unix. Strong education professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science & Mathematics from University of California, Berkeley.

EDUCATION

University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

B.A. in Computer Science

B.A. in Mathematics May 2020 Expected

GPA N/A

Berkeley City College, Berkeley, CA

A.S. in Mathematics with honor May 2018

GPA 4.0 / 4.0

COURSES

Computer Science

Data Structure & Algorithms, Programming Using C++, Python Data Structures (University of Michigan), Java Programming: Solving Problems with Software (Duke University), Programming Foundations with JavaScript, HTML and CSS (Duke University), Introduction to Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science (UC San Diego & National Research)

Mathematics

Calculus I, Calculus II, Calculus III, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, Basic Statistics (University of Amsterdam)

AWARDS & MEMBERSHIP

2018 Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

Information & Communication Technology Scholarship, Peralta Colleges Foundation 2017 - 2018

Academic Honor Student, Berkeley City College Jan. 2017 - May 2018

EXPERIENCE

University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Software Engineer Intern - Threestone Analytics at CITRIS Foundry Jun. 2018 — Aug. 2018

Data Mining and Sentiment Analysis for Environmental Justice in Latin America

University of California Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Undergraduate Researcher - JAMX Project, Berkeley Institute of Data Science

Advisor: Dr. Diego Ponce de Leon Barido

Jan. 2018 — May. 2018

Leading the platform research group with another researcher.

Researching the database, frontend, and the backend.

Enrich the project regards environmental justice with Twitter and SMS APIs.

Berkeley City College, Berkeley, CA

Teaching Assistant – to Dr. Shawn McDougal in "Linear Algebra" Jan. 2018 — May. 2018

Instructing and arranging students during and after class for the contents they have trouble with while studying the subject.

GABRIEL CHEN

Berkeley City College, Berkeley, CA

Tutor - Calculus I, Calculus II, Applied Calculus for Economics, Intro to CS

Instruct students individually and in groups, using various teaching methods such as $\frac{1}{2} \left(\frac{1}{2} \right) = \frac{1}{2} \left(\frac{1}{2} \right) \left(\frac{1}{$

lectures, discussions, and demonstrations.

RELATED PROJECT

Narcissus, Data Mining and Analysis Project

Author Jun. 2018 — Present

Sep. 2016 — Dec. 2016

A project currently running on a Raspberry Pi aim to mine data from Twitter and analysis it for Environmental Justice.

JAMX, Computer Science & Data Science Research Project

Researching Collaborator Jan. 2018 — May. 2018

An undergraduate research project associate with Berkeley Institute of Data Science at UC Berkeley built with React, Flask, PostgreSQL, and Python.

Ada, Raspberry Pi Project

Author May. 2017 – Present

Information provider and daily reminder robot written by Python.

Nice Blog, Jekyll Project

Author Mar. 2016 – May. 2017

Website framework written with Ruby, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

SKILLS

C/C++, Java, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, Linux, Git

LANGUAGES

Fluent in both Mandarin and English. Beginner for Spanish and Japanese.